Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Anthropology, Honors Theses SC4-3521
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Anthropology, honors theses
1986-2009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Anthropology
SC4-3521
2 Linear Feet
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of Anthropology.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of Anthropology.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Anthropology -- Study and teaching.; Student papers.; Stanford University. Department of Anthropology; Stanford University. Department of Anthropology
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Williams, Veronica Christine, The paradox of Black female infertility: an investigation into the perceptions of infertile Black women in Los Angeles, California, 2004 May (Box 1)
  - Tuschman, Avi Samuel, The potato goblin: irony and taboo in the northern Ecuadorian highland Quechua Joke-Narrative, 2002 Jan (Box 1)
  - Scott, Anna Beatrice, Bloco Afro and the construction of an African dispora identity in Salvador, Bahia-Brazil: a contextual reading of the retention theory and ethnicity through dance, 1991 spr (Box 1)
  - Razon, Na'amah, Vettai Noi: making AIDS Indian; a study of the use of Siddha Medicine on AIDS/HIV patients in Tamil Nadu, India, 2004 May (Box 1)
  - Najera, Jennifer. Las mujeres solas de Tepatitlán: the effects of migration on Mexican women, 1997 May (Box 1)
  - Morales, Paola Z., La dolce vita? Changing lives of Cape Verdean immigrants in Florence, 1998 May (Box 1)
  - Mei, Angie, The (de)construction of Bangalore: the city as commodity, 1998 Jun (Box 1)
  - Macias, Julia, Somos la protesta: cultural expresión and protest of Guanatos gangs, 1997 May (Box 1)
  - Gregg, Jessica, The Watsonville cannery strike and the Mexican garment workers' movement: a comparison, 1988 May (Box 1)
  - Greene, Solomon J., Olympia was not a city: poverty, planning, and the restructuring of urban space in Olympic Atlanta, 1996 May (Box 1)
  - Bandy, Matthew Sebastian, Style, signification and social control; a case from the Tarascan Sierra, 1992 May (Box 1)
  - Borchardt, Annette Nikki, The Paiute Indian tribe of Utah: ethnic boundary formation and cultural loss, 2004 May (Box 1)
  - Dubal, Sam, The neoliberalization of football: rethinking Neoliberalism through the commercialization of the beautiful game, 2008 May (Box 2)
  - Collingwood, Ria, Akwaaba Onua Baa ne Onua Barima: Welcome Sister and Brother; contesting imaginaries of Pan Africanism in Post-Colonial Ghana, circa 2006 (Box 2)
  - Gillum, Kathleen, Taking education and economy to bed: causes and implications of sexual behavior change in modern Ireland, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Ludwig, Kathryn A., Stylistic variation in Maya hieroglyphs: a statistical approach, 2008 May (Box 2)
  - Remtulla, Aly, (Dis)placing Khojahs: forging identities, revitalizing Islam, and crafting global Ismailism, 1998 Jun (Box 2)
  - Nelson, Julia Ka'iulani, Mingas, Marimba, and Menguante: social impacts of timber commercialization in the Awá community of Pambilar, Ecuador, 0 (Box 2)
  - Snowdon, Ashley H., Hiring wives: the reformulation of kinship in dual-career couples, 1998 May (Box 2)
  - Nado, Kristin, Trade, culture, and power in prehistoric Peru: the chemical charicterization [sic] of obsidian from Chavín de Huántar, 2007 May (Box 2)
  - Saffer, Sarah, The Tenon heads of Chavín de Huantar: evidence for drug use at a pre-historic temple site, 1998 May (Box 2)
  - Ho, Eng Seng and G. William Skinner, Problems of identity among the overseas Chinese: a historical examination of the Baba Chinese in Penang, 1986 Jun (Box 2)
  - Das, Sonia, A crisis of filth in West Bengal: transformation of resistance through discourses of development, corruption, and environmentalism, 1999 Spring (Box 2)
  - Menon, Anupama, Blood and belonging: Indian American women activists and the politics of location, 1999 Jun (Box 2)
  - Bryer, Sarah, Social maps and theoretical grids: women and space in a Turkish squatter settlement, 1989 May (Box 3)
  - Burson, Elizabeth, Architecture and changing labor capacity at Chavín de Huantar, 1996 May (Box 3)
  - Jacobson, Jill, Migration for marriage and cash: Bobo maids in Bamako, Mali, 1986 Jun (Box 3)
  - Jacobson, Jill, Sentinels on the walls: the intersection of politics and religious identity among American Christian Zionists in Jerusalem, 1993 spr (Box 3)
  - Ballinger, Patricia. Italian Pentecost: receiving the Word in human flesh; the development of nationalistic religion at Fiume, 1919-21, 1990 May (Box 3)
  - Ortman, Scott G., Architectural wood use and its implications for basketmaker settlement and ecology: the view from Zini, New Mexico, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Stout, Noelle Monet, Reaching Doma Ling: Tibetan Buddhist nuns in exile, 1998 Spring (Box 3)
  - Amezcua, Alejandro, Latino/a transgenderism and identities: the reconfiguration of gender and sex categories, 1999 Spring (Box 3)
  - Gewurz, Elizabeth Suzanne, How do social movements cohere? A case study of a contemporary agricultural cooperative in Xiltila, San Luis Potosi, Mexico, 1999 May (Box 3)
  - Mandeville-Gamble, Steven, Gay men and their relationships: a discussion of the division of labor in non-traditional couples, 1987 May (Box 3)
  - Schmid, Kristen, "Nimble fingers:" Chinese women's familial roles and multinational factory employment, 1995 Spring (Box 3)
  - Patty, Lauren, Transitions and traditions: health care benefits and practices of the indigenous tribes of Northern Baja California, 2000 May (Box 4)
  - Iskander, Natasha Nefertiti, Walking in two worlds with one spirit: Alaska native models of recovery and definitions of culture, 1994 Jun (Box 4)
  - Weeks, Dana Kim-Ngan, Slim women: AIDS, representation, and the empowerment of Ugandan women, 1994 May (Box 4)
  - Yeatts, Dale Jeremy, Economy, culture, and ethnicity in the "Vertical" Andes: the archaeological reconstruction of Tiwanaku-Moquegua Valley interaction during the Middle Horizon Period in the Andes, 1994 Jun (Box 4)
  - Iwashita, Ann M., A source of strength: the advancement of Japanese American women in Hawaii, 2000 May (Box 4)
  - Bradbury, Zoë Ida, Farming at the margins: the struggle to sustain family agriculture in Langlois, Oregon and La Estrella, Chile, 2001 Spring (Box 4)
  - Swartz, Diana T., Rape: the East/West debate in Germany from 1970 - present, 1997 Spring (Box 4)
  - Montenegro, Maya, Crossing barriers: HIV prevention for the Latino community in the Bay Area, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Carvalho, Micah Hoku, The Global gaze of UNAIDS: positioning th "Pacific" within discourses of linear development and post-colonial identity, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Desai, Parijat, Garba and Raas today: urban conceptualizations and control of Gujarati folk dance, 1992 Spring (Box 4)
  - Huyck, Teddy, El Camino de Santiago: pilgrim transformations, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Toutonghi, Stephen, A study of identity change on Alaska's Kenai Peninsula, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Aziz, Amna Suraya, The Pan-African health discourse: an anthropologogical look at the lived health and immigration experience of African immigrants in the San Francisco Bay Area, 2009 May (Box 4)
  - Kang, David, Bumpkins and eggheads: a cultural look at Livermore in the 1950's, 1987 Jan (Box 4)